Sudheer Kumar D

Data warehouse Architect

Summary

Data Warehouse Architect:

As Data warehouse Architect, built various Data marts and worked on providing easy access to Hedge funds and financial data to the Leading Hedge Funds Administrators. The Data Warehouse was more than 30 Terabyte in size and features powerful analytical tools, flexible reporting capabilities and leverages the corporation's authoritative sources of information. Created Data warehouse on Netezza with various heterogeneous sources includes: Sybase ASE, Flat File, Web service.

Experience

Manager at Sapient

August 2016 - Present (8 months)

Senior Associate at Sapient

November 2012 - July 2016 (3 years 9 months)

- # One of the architects of Leading Hedge Funds Data warehouse. Worked on Hedge Fund Administration project from inception. Designed, developed and implemented the data warehouse solution from scratch.
- # Managed the complete project with a team size of over 15 persons.
- # Analyzed the existing systems and the business user requirements for tactical and strategic needs.
- # Created the Multi-Dimensional data model (STAR Schema) and enhanced it to meet the growing requirements due to various corporate groups accessing the data. Designed various Type-2 dimensions.
- # Created the ETL architecture from the scratch and provided strategy related to data cleansing, data quality and data consolidation
- # Interacted with the business users on regular basis to consolidate and analyze the requirements and present them the design results.
- # Understand appropriate technologies, tools and optimization techniques and models.

Exceptionally good knowledge of Oracle database product and its architecture.

Technical Consultant at JDA Software

September 2011 - November 2012 (1 year 3 months)

Worked as a Technical Consultant.

Designed and implemented Solutions using i2 TMS product for various Clients.

Optimized the Solution with multiple destinations using i2 proprietary approach.

Designed and created Business Intelligence Reports for Accruals generations and also for Data Mining to help Clients in researching their business needs.

Also helping Architects in designing and participated in various Business discussions.

Sr Software Engineer at Mindtree

August 2010 - September 2011 (1 year 2 months)

Associate Consultant at Oracle

August 2008 - August 2010 (2 years 1 month)

Skills & Expertise

Compliance Management Reporting Systerm

FATCA

GDD

Hedge Funds

Data Warehousing

Netezza DB

Netezza Striper

SQL

Microsoft SQL Server

PL/SQL

Sybase Adaptive Server

Oracle

Unix Shell Scripting

Performance Tuning

Databases

Shell Scripting

SSIS

Business Analysis

Java

Requirements Analysis

Business Intelligence

ETL

 \mathbf{C}

Agile Methodologies

Education

Dayananda Sagar College Of Engineering

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer and Information Sciences, General, 2004 - 2008

MSEMH School Yemmiganur

Bachelor of Engineering

Sudheer Kumar D

Data warehouse Architect



Contact Sudheer Kumar on LinkedIn